{
  "q1": [
    {
      "question": "In one battle fought in this state, British forces led by Charles Mawhood surrounded and killed Hugh Mercer after mistaking him for George Washington. At another battle in this state, the actions of Mary Hays may have inspired popular accounts of Molly Pitcher. The Hessian commander Johann Rall was killed at another battle fought in this state in December 1776 that was preceded by Washington’s crossing of the Delaware. For ten points, name this state home to the Revolutionary War battles of Princeton and Trenton.",
      "answer": "New Jersey"
    },
    {
      "question": "One man involved in this event had previously fled to Paterborn and requested reinstatement from the subject of this event. Empress Irene of Constantinople was de-legitimized after this event, and Einhard declared that its subject would “not have set foot” in St. Peter’s Basilica had he known what would take place. This event took place on Christmas Day, 800. For ten points, name this ceremony in which Pope Leo III created the Holy Roman Empire by elevating the son of Pepin the Short to the throne.",
      "answer": [
        "Crowning of Charlemagne",
        "Coronation of Charlemagne"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "This country’s current President led a 1983 coup against Shehu Shagari. Abubakar Shekau leads a terrorist organization based in this country, which in 2014 attacked a school in Chibok, abducting 276 girls. Muhammad Buhari replaced Goodluck Jonathan as this country’s President in 2015. For ten points, name this African country where, in 2011, Boko Haram bombed a UN compound in Abuja.",
      "answer": "Nigeria"
    },
    {
      "question": "One man involved in this scandal wrote “We want more friends in this Congress.” Aaron Perry investigated this scandal, which was exposed by a letter from Henry McComb to the New York Sun. It involved Congressman Oakes Ames’ use of stock in a railroad company as bribes, and was revealed during the 1872 Presidential election. For ten points, name this scandal that ended Schuyler Colfax’s political career but failed to prevent Ulysses Grant’s re-election.",
      "answer": "Credit Mobilier of America scandal"
    },
    {
      "question": "This man was the first athlete to run for 2,000 yards in an NFL season in 1973. He had to auction his 1968 Heisman Trophy, earned at USC, to pay the estate of Ronald Goldman as a result of a civil suit in 1997, two years after Alan Dershowitz and Johnnie Cochran defended this man in the “Trial of the Century”. For ten points, name this former Buffalo Bill running back who was acquitted of murdering his ex-wife, Nicole Brown, in 1995.",
      "answer": "Orenthal James “O.J.” Simpson"
    },
    {
      "question": "One man captured during this event was given the option to kill himself but refused, leading him to be shot by Michael Lippert. Franz von Papen’s Marburg Speech heavily influenced this event, whose planners called it Operation Hummingbird. This event led to the death of George Strasser and others who suppressed the 1923 Beer Hall Putsch. Its main target was Ernst Rohm and it led to the rise of a force under Heinrich Himmler. For ten points, name this purge of the SA by the Nazi Party.",
      "answer": [
        "Night of the Long Knives",
        "Operation Hummingbird before it is read"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "In the 1800s, Leslie Keeley discovered that a mixture of sodium and this element’s chloride was effective in treating addictions, including alcoholism. Fritz Haber suggested a way to pay off German war reparations by collecting this element from seawater. Geiger and Marsden disproved the plum pudding atomic model by bombarding alpha particles into a thin foil of this metal. For ten points, name this precious metal with chemical symbol Au.",
      "answer": "gold"
    },
    {
      "question": "This man’s doctoral thesis studied the degree of brain myelinization in white rats. With Harvey Karr, this man conditioned rats to run into walls when food was moved from its previous location in a maze. This engineer of the Kerplunk! experiment supposedly invented the coffee break in an ad campaign. With Rosalie Rayner, he conditioned a nine-month old boy to fear furry objects in the “Little Albert” experiment. For ten points, name this American psychologist who founded the school of behaviorism.",
      "answer": "John Broadus Watson"
    },
    {
      "question": "Folk singer Dave van Ronk was arrested during this event. The Mattachine Society tried to control rioting after this event. Allen Ginsberg said that some protesters during this event had “lost that wounded look”. The death of Judy Garland has been proposed as a starting point for this event. An NYPD raid on a bar triggered, for ten points, what series of riots in Greenwich Village in 1969 that began the modern gay rights movement?",
      "answer": "Stonewall Inn riots or the raid on the Stonewall Inn itself"
    },
    {
      "question": "In 1569, Francis Xavier’s men negotiated the use of this city as a Portuguese port, and it briefly became a Jesuit colony during the late Sengoku period. The Bockscar flew to this city after leaving cloud-obscured Kokura, where it released a plutonium bomb called the “Fat Man”. For ten points, name this Japanese city, the second target of a U.S. atomic bomb after Hiroshima.",
      "answer": "Nagasaki"
    }
  ],
  "q2": [
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "Miguel Barbachano advocated for this state’s independence until a Caste War against Mayan forces, which included a sacking of its city of Valladolid [vay-yah-doh-leed]. Studies in the 1970s found shocked quartz in the northern area of this state, centered near the city of Chicxulub [chick-shu-lub] and dating to the K-Pg boundary. This Mexican state, with capital Merida, is the hypothesized site of the impact that killed the dinosaurs. For ten points, name this Mexican state on a namesake peninsula that juts into the Gulf of Mexico.",
        "answer": "Yucatan or Yucatan Peninsula"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "This resort city on the northeastern tip of the Yucatan Peninsula, north of Playa del Carmen, remodeled its city grid after being significantly damaged by Hurricane Gilbert in 1988.",
        "answer": "Cancu´n"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This country was attacked by England and France during its Disaster Year, which resulted in the lynching of Cornelius and Jan de Witt. One general from this country emphasized combined arms to win the Battle of Nieuwpoort, although he avoided battle with the Duke of Parma during the 80 Years’ War. This home of Maurice of Nassau was formed from the 17 Provinces, and was led during its independence war by William the Silent. For ten points, name this country, which was ruled by the House of Orange from Amsterdam.",
        "answer": "The Netherlands"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "William the Silent was given this position, originally the representative of the Spanish king in the Netherlands. It evolved to essentially becoming the highest executive official in the Netherlands.",
        "answer": "Stadtholder"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "Alfred Moore and William Cushing recused themselves from this case, whose ruling affirmed that the Supreme Court did not have the right to issue writs of mandamus, thereby rendering Section 13 of the Judiciary Act of 1789 unconstitutional. The plaintiff in this case had been denied a commission of judgeship in the District of Columbia, which he had received as one of the “midnight appointments” of John Adams. For ten points, name this Supreme Court case presided by John Marshall that established judicial review.",
        "answer": "Marbury v. Madison"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "The concept of judicial review had been endorsed in Federalist Paper No. 78 by this founding father.",
        "answer": "Alexander Hamilton"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "Daniel Mendoza introduced defensive movement into this sport in the late 18th century, and John Douglas, Marquess of Queensbury, decreased violence in this sport with new rules in the 19th century. The retired James Jeffries was hailed as a “Great White Hope” to defeat James Johnson, a black champion of this sport in 1910. Another champion of this sport refused to join the military during the Vietnam War, citing his Muslim beliefs. For ten points, name this sport whose champions have included Muhammad Ali.",
        "answer": "boxing"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "In the 1974 Rumble in the Jungle, Muhammad Ali defeated this grilling entrepreneur to regain the world heavyweight championship.",
        "answer": "George Foreman"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "A “re-education movement” by one side after this war killed over 100,000 suspected collaborators in the Bodo League massacre. The Hangang Bridge was destroyed during this conflict by one side to prevent an offensive, leading to the deaths of over 1,000 refugees. Aerial combat in this war took place over MiG Alley, and American entrance into this war led to heavy casualties at the Battles of Heartbreak Ridge and Pork Chop Hill. For ten points, name this 1950 to 1953 war that was ended by an armistice which established a demilitarized zone on its namesake peninsula.",
        "answer": "Korean War"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "In Operation Chromite, Douglas MacArthur led an amphibious landing at this city in 1950, then went on to re-capture Seoul.",
        "answer": "Inchon"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "During the Vietnam War, Tony Shafrazi defaced this painting with the phrase “KILL LIES ALL.” A tapestry of this work commissioned by Nelson Rockefeller was covered during a Colin Powell speech at the United Nations building. A naked lightbulb illuminates this work, in which a flower grows out of a hand clutching a broken sword below a bull and a screaming horse. For ten points, name this large Pablo Picasso painting created in response to the bombing of a namesake town during the Spanish Civil War.",
        "answer": "Guernica"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Pablo Picasso helped to found the Cubist movement alongside this once-Fauvist creator of Violin and Candlestick.",
        "answer": "Georges Braque"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "In this country, Ingrid Betancourt was kidnapped for over six years by the Revolutionary Armed Forces. The killing of Jorge Eliecer Gaitan sparked a ten-year civil war in this country known as La Violencia. Juan Manuel Santos currently leads this country, where possibly the richest criminal in history created a prolific cocaine cartel. Pablo Escobar operated in, for ten points, what South American country with capital Bogota?",
        "answer": "Colombia"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Escobar’s cartel was based in this second largest Colombian city, where Escobar was killed in a firefight in 1993.",
        "answer": "Medellin"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This man commissioned Victor Baltard to renovate the market of Les Halles, and this man supported the Perriere brothers in forming the Cr´edit Mobilier. Derided by Victor Hugo, this man was inspired by Hyde Park to refurbish the Bois de Boulogne and the Bois de Vincennes as part of this man’s renovation of his capital, supervised by Baron Haussmann. This supporter of Emperor Maximilian of Mexico would be forced to abdicate after surrendering at the Battle of Sedan. For ten points, name this last emperor of France, nephew to the first.",
        "answer": "Napol´eon III"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Napol´eon III first rose to power by being elected president of this government, which overthrew the last king of France, Louis-Phillipe d’Orl´eans, in 1848.",
        "answer": "Second Republic of France"
      }
    }
  ],
  "q3": [
    {
      "category": "Calvin Coolidge was...",
      "prompt": "Name the calvin coolidge was......",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Vice President under what man, whose death elevated Coolidge to the Presidency in 1923?",
          "answer": "Warren Harding"
        },
        {
          "question": "succeeded as President in 1929 by what man, his Secretary of Commerce?",
          "answer": "Herbert Hoover"
        },
        {
          "question": "was the only man to defeat what future President in a national election, on the Vice Presidential tickets in 1920?",
          "answer": [
            "Franklin Delano Roosevelt",
            "FDR"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "praised for ending a 1919 police strike in what city?",
          "answer": "Boston"
        },
        {
          "question": "served by what Secretary of State, who signed a 1928 peace pact with a Aristide Briand?",
          "answer": "Frank Kellogg"
        },
        {
          "question": "offended what union, led by Big Bill Haywood, in his mediation of the “Bread and Roses” strike?",
          "answer": [
            "Industrial Workers of the World or IWW",
            "Wobblies"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "opposed in the 1924 election by what Progressive Wisconsin senator?",
          "answer": "Robert La Follette, Sr."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "Il Risorgimento",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "capital city whose 1871 capture finished the Italian unification.",
          "answer": "Rome"
        },
        {
          "question": "city, home to the Uffizi gallery, which replaced Turin as a temporary capital.",
          "answer": "Florence"
        },
        {
          "question": "first king of the unified Italy.",
          "answer": "Victor Emmanuel II"
        },
        {
          "question": "country that controlled Lombardy-Venetia until 1866 and was ruled by Emperor Franz Joseph I.",
          "answer": "Austrian Empire"
        },
        {
          "question": "leader of the Redshirts and the Expedition of a Thousand.",
          "answer": "Giuseppe Garibaldi"
        },
        {
          "question": "noble Prime Minister of Piedmont-Sardinia, who arranged for French intervention.",
          "answer": "Camillo Benso, Count di Cavour"
        },
        {
          "question": "journalist and founder of the secret, pro-unification Young Italy society.",
          "answer": "Giuseppe Mazzini"
        },
        {
          "question": "southern kingdom whose independence was lost at the Siege of Gaeta.",
          "answer": "Kingdom of the Two Sicilies"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "Simon Bolivar",
      "prompt": "Name...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "either capital city of the country which was named in his honor in 1825.",
          "answer": [
            "Sucre",
            "La Paz"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "the self-appointed position Bolivar took with his Organic Decree, also taken by Roman republic rulers during emergencies.",
          "answer": "dictator"
        },
        {
          "question": "the Caribbean capital city, from where he wrote the “Letter from Jamaica.”",
          "answer": "Kingston"
        },
        {
          "question": "the “great” country that gained its independence from Spain in 1819 at Boyaca but broke apart in 1831",
          "answer": "Gran Colombia"
        },
        {
          "question": "the July 1822 conference where Bolivar discussed the future of Peru.",
          "answer": "Guayaquil Conference"
        },
        {
          "question": "the Argentinian general who resigned as protector of Peru at that conference.",
          "answer": "Jose de San Martin"
        },
        {
          "question": "the 1813 decree that ordered the murder of Spanish-born civilians in Venezuela.",
          "answer": "Decree of War to the Death"
        },
        {
          "question": "the 1824 battle in Peru that ended Spanish rule in South America.",
          "answer": "Battle of Ayacucho"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  "q4": [
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) One country launched the Mega Rice Project on this island, resulting in the mass drainage of its peat swamps. The southern portion of this island is referred to as (20 pts)",
        "Kalimantan, and the Wallace line separates this island from Sulawesi. The Crocker Range is home to Mount (10 pts)",
        "Kinabalu, its highest point. The Philippines once claimed the province of Sabah on, for ten points, what island divided between Indonesia, Brunei and Malaysia?"
      ],
      "answer": "Borneo"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This speech was delivered shortly after an incendiary speech by “Pitchfork Ben” Tillman failed to sway the audience. This speech notes “It is the issue of 1776 over again” in describing the need for (20 pts)",
        "international agreement on its central issue, which was supported by the Bland-Allison Act. This speech, given in Chicago at the (10 pts)",
        "Democratic National Convention, uses the Biblical image of a crown of thorns in its climax. For ten points, name this 1896 William Jennings Bryan speech which advocated for free silver and proclaimed “you shall not crucify mankind” upon the title structure."
      ],
      "answer": "Cross of Gold speech"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This composer wrote a study for 23 strings in response to the destruction of the Munich Opera House and firebombing of Dresden. This composer of Metamorphosen spent two years as the head of the State Music Bureau for the (20 pts)",
        "Nazis. He depicted a German trickster folk hero in the tone poem Till Eulenspiegel, while another of his works opens with the “Sunrise” fanfare and includes sections titled after chapters of a (10 pts)",
        "Friedrich Nietzsche book. For ten points, what German composer wrote Also Sprach Zarathustra?"
      ],
      "answer": "Richard Strauss"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This man “learned good morals” from his grandfather Verus, according to a work written while on campaign in Pannonia against the Quadi. During this man’s rule, the Antonine Plague killed his co-ruler, Lucius (20 pts)",
        "Verus. This father of Commodus wrote a 12-book work based on the ideas of a school founded by (10 pts)",
        "Zeno of Citium. For ten points, name this last of the Five Great Emperors and author of the Stoic book Meditations."
      ],
      "answer": "Marcus Aurelius Antoninus Augustus"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This politician’s “Syracuse speech” defended the Fugitive Slave Law in the Compromise of 1850, earning him ire from Horace Mann. His “Plea for Harmony and Peace” speech was defended by John F. Kennedy in Profiles in Courage. The (20 pts)",
        "Know-Nothing Party put this man’s name on the ballot in the 1852 election. This senator, who declared “Liberty and Union, (10 pts)",
        "now and forever, one and inseparable,” signed a treaty setting Maine’s border with Baron Ashburton. For ten points, name this Massachusetts orator who formed the Great Triumvirate with Calhoun and Clay."
      ],
      "answer": "Daniel Webster"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This man climbed the “Mount of the Hermit” while in Quanzhou after receiving support from the Delhi sultan Muhammad bin Tughluq. This ambassador to the Yuan Dynasty fought off Alfonso XI at Gibraltar in a defense of his (20 pts)",
        "native Morocco and was commanded by Abu Inan Faris to allow (10 pts)",
        "Ibn Juzayy to document his experiences. For ten points, name this author of the Rihla, an account of his travels through the medieval Muslim world."
      ],
      "answer": "Muhammad Ibn Battuta"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) The original recitation of this work supposedly caused one listener to faint upon hearing the name of her son, Marcellus, mentioned. The executors of this work were ordered to publish this work after its author’s death, regardless of his wishes, and this work’s patron was the nobleman (20 pts)",
        "Maecenas. This work’s title figure wins the hand of Lavinia after defeating Turnus, and (10 pts)",
        "Augustus championed this work because he saw himself as an incarnate of its hero, who escaped from the Trojan War. For ten points, name this epic poem by Virgil about the title Trojan prince."
      ],
      "answer": "The Aeneid"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) Hans and Sophie Scholl, part of the White Rose group, were based in this city and executedfortheiranti-NazileafletsduringWorldWarII. (20 pts)",
        "Dachau, thefirstconcentration camp, was located close to this city, and the Nazi Party’s national headquarters, the Brown house, was located at the center of this city. This city was targeted by (10 pts)",
        "Black September in a 1972 incident that occurred while it was hosting the Summer Olympics. For ten points, name this German city, the site of a namesake “Massacre” of Israeli athletes."
      ],
      "answer": "Munich"
    }
  ]
}